Thilanka Rodrigo

San Francisco, California, United States



developer.thilanka.rodrigo@gmail.com



785-492-1927



linkedin.com/in/thilanka-rodrigo-116090143

Summary

With broad experience in IT Support and Full Stack Web Development, I bring a unique blend of skills to the tech industry. Expert in MERN Stack, Python, AWS, and various operating systems, I excel in problem resolution, network administration, and software installation. My time in the US Army nurtured adaptability and rapid learning, essential in today's fast-paced IT environment. I'm committed to leveraging my diverse expertise to improve IT support, contributing to overall organizational efficiency and productivity.

Experience

IT Support Specialist

Geeks on Site

Jul 2023 - Present (1 month)

Tasked with maintaining computer systems, troubleshooting errors, maintaining internet connectivity, running diagnostic tests, maintaining servers, repairing computer hardware, and providing technical support. Responsibilities include the installation and configuration of TV, surveillance, automation and networked systems in mainly residential, but also commercial spaces.

Frontend Web Developer

Freelance

Apr 2020 - Present (3 years 4 months)

As a Freelance Frontend Web Developer, I specialize in creating dynamic and engaging web applications using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js). My expertise lies in developing intuitive user interfaces, ensuring seamless user experience, and implementing responsive design principles for optimal viewing across devices. With a knack for problem-solving and a commitment to efficiency, I'm able to deliver robust solutions that cater to specific client needs.

Weterans Service Representative

City College of San Francisco

Jun 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 year 7 months)

- -Assisted veterans with navigating numerous benefit programs and entitlement criteria.
- -Helped improve end user productivity by completing triage, offering advice, teaching and developing solutions to common challenges with office products and capabilities
- -Provided hardware break/fix support and warranty support for current desktop, laptop, tablets and workstation devices

★ Healthcare Specialist

US Army

Oct 2015 - Oct 2017 (2 years 1 month)

As a Healthcare Specialist I was responsible for

- -interviewing patients, recording their medical histories, taking vitals, and preparing blood samples for lab analysis.
- -administering intravenous solutions to soldiers during long movements and training.

Additionally, helped improve end user productivity by completing triage, offering advice, teaching and developing solutions to common challenges with office products and capabilities

🗶 Healthcare Specialist

US Army

Apr 2014 - Oct 2015 (1 year 7 months)

As a Healthcare Specialist I was responsible for

- -administering emergency medical treatment
- -preparing patients and operating rooms for surgery
- -maintaining updated health records
- -using ticketing software

Additionally, helped improve end user productivity by completing triage, offering advice, teaching and developing solutions to common challenges with office products and capabilities

Education



Code Immersives

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack Web Development

May 2022 - May 2023

Completed a rigorous Full Stack Web Development Program.

Coursera

Meta Frontend Web Developer Certificate, Computer Software Engineering

Apr 2023 - Aug 2023

Pursuing a Professional Certificate in Front-End Development, a comprehensive 9-course series designed by Meta.

City College of San Francisco

Computer Science Jan 2018 - Jan 2020

Coursera

Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate, Cybersecurity

Apr 2023 - Aug 2023

- -Understand the importance of cybersecurity practices and their impact for organizations.
- -Identify common risks, threats, and vulnerabilities, as well as techniques to mitigate them.
- -Protect networks, devices, people, and data from unauthorized access and cyberattacks using Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) tools.
- -Gain hands-on experience with Python, Linux, and SQL.

Licenses & Certifications

- Learning Full-Stack JavaScript Development: MongoDB, Node, and React LinkedIn
- in Google Cloud Foundations LinkedIn
- CompTIA A+ CompTIA
 Issued May 2017 Expires May 2020
 COMP001021157250
- CompTIA Security+ CompTIA
 Issued Apr 2017 Expires Apr 2020
 COMP001021157250
- CompTIA Network+ CompTIA
 Issued May 2017 Expires May 2020
 COMP001021157250
- Career Essentials in System Administration by Microsoft and LinkedIn Microsoft
- in IT Help Desk for Beginners LinkedIn
- Google IT Support Certificate (2023) Coursera
 CGHG4YZWRLUP
- Advanced React Coursera
 XPXVW48VUEHC
- Version Control Coursera
 K3LACUGNJAAT
- Programming with JavaScript Coursera
 87ANV3WPPLRN

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Front-End Development • React.js • IT Support • Communication • Leadership • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • IT Operations • Node.js • Customer Service